ABHISHEK BEHERA

🔖 +1-(404)-268-5462 | 🖄 abehera1992@gmail.com | www.abhishekb.dev

SUMMARY:

5 years of professional experience in software industry as Software Developer/Automation Engineer in the areas of analysis, design, development and testing of web applications. Strong leadership and team management skills to deliver successive outcomes, whereby, positioning organizations and products for success. Quickly able to learn and master new technologies with proven success working in both team and self-directed setting.

HIGHLIGHTS:

- Proficient in Web Application Development and
- Preferred technology stack: Microsoft .NET Standard/Core 2.0 and above, MEAN, Java-Spring boot.
- Web testing (Unit/End-to-end): Selenium-Nunit-Specflow supporting BDD.
- Agile development methodologies.

- Interface design and Implementation.
- Self-Analytical and goal oriented.
- Quick learner and a team player.
- Product development with customer centric features.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

SAL SITTLES.	
.Net Technologies	.Net Framework: 4.5 and above, Core 2.0 and above, Web API/MVC Controller, MS Identity.
Languages	C#, Java, C++, Dart, XAML.
Web Technologies	HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap 4 & 5, Material design, Angular, JavaScript (ES5 and ES6), Typescript, jQuery, Rxjs, JWT, Auth0, GraphQL.
Mobile Technologies	Xamarin Forms (Xaml), Flutter
Database	SQL Server 2016/2012 rc-2, MySQL, Oracle 11g, MongoDB, DynamoDB, Amazon RDS, Firebase NoSql DB.
SDLC Tools/Others	Jenkins, Docker, Confluence, JIRA, MS Project, Axure, VSTS AGILE Planning, Smartsheet.
Reporting Services	SSRS, Tableau.
Web Server	IIS 6.0/ 7.0, Nginx, Apache.
Cloud Technologies	VSTS, TFS, Azure, Firebase, Amazon S3.
Version Control	SVN, GIT and GITHUB.
IDE	Visual Studio: 2015/2017/2019, IntelliJ, ATOM, VSCode, SSMS.
Design and Modeling	MVC 4.5/ 5.0, MVVM.
Test Automation	Selenium, Nunit, Specflow - Cucumber BDD (Gherkin), Katalon, Saucelabs.

EXPERIENCE:

Software-Automation Engineer Ingenious Med Inc. – Atlanta, U.S.A

June 2018 to current

- Updated, modified and expended existing web application IMBill: The enterprise application (IMBill) majorly focuses of simplifying clinical workflow for healthcare domain by providing industry leading solution such as: Practice and Enterprise solution which provides features like charge capture, care coordination and quality reporting and expand the communication and coordination features across the enterprise to all care team members.
- Drove continual improvement to application architecture by refactoring legacy codes and adhering to today's coding and security standards.
- Implemented and tested enhancement feature requests to enhance product functionality.
- Analyzed requirements and used systematic approaches to implement and document the tasks.
- Primarily worked in improving application's test automation framework to address constant feature updates using selenium-NUnit, Specflow & Jenkins, whereby, achieving 90% over-all test pass rate which covers 350 test-cases spanning 4000 test scenarios.

Development Tools, Methodologies & Environments: Agile approach, Microsoft TFS, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, .NET MVC, MS SQL Server TSQL/SQL, Selenium, NUnit, Spec-flow, Jenkins.

Systems Architect (.NET - Angular) Macy's System and Technology – Atlanta, U.S.A

December 2017 – May 2018

- Design and architecting Macy's HR management application (INSITE-MyDay) Availability & Accommodation using Angular 2 and above and ASP.NET(C#) MVC.
- Developed a standalone Clocking application towards employee clocking and scheduling using Angular, ASP.NET Core
 2.1 and Java.
- Worked with Angular 4 using Angular CLI and .NET Core templates, generated various components, routes, and services and structured the application code based on Component based architecture.
- Developed custom Pipes and Directives for addressing data filtering in the UI against a given set of rules and satisfying required business needs and functionality.
- Successfully designed and developed RESTFul web services (Dependency Injection) to interact with API's to perform create, update and delete records, enforcing current industry standards and practices.
- Updated, modified and optimized database functions, scripts, stored procedures and triggers to support application development using Oracle SQL Developer & Oracle 11g.

Development Tools, Methodologies & Environments: Agile approach, JIRA, Confluence, Axure, Angular 2 and above, HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript/Typescript, Bootstrap, ASP.NET MVC (C#), Core 2.0, Java, Oracle-PL/SQL, Web API's, Kronos HCM.

Web Developer – ID0 Netrix LLc. – Pune, INDIA

June 2014 to July 2015

- Successful design of GUI for Pharmalnsight[™]- A suite of solutions providing enhanced visibility, security and oversight over pharmaceutical supply-chain for enhanced tracking, management and transparency for the client – Sun Pharceuticals, NJ, U.S.A
- Successfully assisted in building 2 core modules of the suite using ASP.NET MVC and Entity framework for tracking and managing Drug Trial Reporting, medical assets and inventory management.
- Optimizing architecture design based on OOPS principle and implementing best software design practices for implementing dependency injection and inversion principle while creating application services.
- Experience with SQL Server, SQL database programming concepts, including database architecture, stored procedures, query optimization, views, UDF and checking performance/scalability of database.
- Collaborated in projects which involved web-based enterprise software development in an agile driven environment.

Development Tools, Methodologies & Environments: Object-Oriented Design (OOD), Project Management, UML Design, Confluence/JIRA, Agile-SCRUM Approach using VSTS, ASP.NET(C#) MVC, Microsoft, AngularJS.

MISCELLANIOUS EXPERIENCE:

- NASA Boeing Aerospace: Software Associate Intern, Houston, TX. [June 2016 August 2016]
- HCL Technologies Ltd: .NET Developer, Bhubaneswar, OD, INDIA. [May 2013 April 2014]
- Microsoft India: Community Evangelist, Bengaluru, KA, INDIA. [January 2012 December 2014]
- Pearson Educomp: IT Analyst Intern, Bhubaneswar, OD, INDIA. [September 2011 July 2012]

EDUCATION:

Master's in Software Engineering - 2017, University of Houston, Clear-Lake - GPA: 3.92/4.00

Worked full-time as a Teaching Assistant in Computer Science field of programs.

Bachelor's in Computer Science and Engineering – 2014, ITER, S'O'A University - GPA: 3.8/4.00